Gwachi Elebeke

+1 416-879-8406

<u>gwachukwuelebeke@gmail.com</u> • <u>https://linkedin.com/in/gwachukwu</u> / <u>https://bit.ly/Gwachukwu</u> Canada

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer with experience working with HTML, CSS3/SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Node.JS, Express.JS, C#, .NET, NoSQL (MongoDB), and SQL (MySQL, Postgres, etc.). I build amazing and user-friendly applications. I enjoy working on new products and occasionally taking on new challenges that push me to grow. I am open to relocation within Canada.

EDUCATION

Graduate Certificate - Mobile Application Development

2023 - 2024

Cambrian College of Applied Arts and Technology • Sudbury, Ontario, Canada **Awards:** President's Honour Roll, awarded for achieving a 4.0/4.0 GPA

Bachelor's Degree - Industrial Chemistry

2010 - 2015

University of Benin • Benin City, Nigeria

SKILLS

HTML, CSS3, SASS, JAVASCRIPT, TYPESCRIPT, REACT, REACT NATIVE, REDUX, VUE, BOOTSTRAP, TAILWIND CSS, NEXT.JS, NODEJS, EXPRESS, SQL (Postgres, MySQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), C#, .NET, AWS, Azure.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Mar 2022 – July 2024

VFD Tech Limited. • Lagos, Nigeria

- Led full-stack web development for various subsidiaries under VFD Group PLC, delivering software solutions that empowered the group's businesses.
- Designed and developed intuitive interfaces to enhance user experience.
- Engineered Restful APIs and microservices to support seamless integration and data exchange.
- Mentored junior developers and interns guiding them to sharpen their skills and be better.
- Collaborated effectively using Bitbucket, Jira, and Teams to optimize team productivity and project management.

Front-end Web Developer

Apr 2021 - Mar 2022

Miraton Matador Group • Lagos, Nigeria

- Developed and maintained the company's online banking application, ensuring seamless functionality and user experience.
- Implemented innovative user-facing features for MMG subsidiaries' web applications, enhancing usability and efficiency.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to ensure the technical feasibility of designs, resulting in visually appealing and functional interfaces.

Cerebre Digital Limited • Lagos, Nigeria

 Developed full-stack applications using HTML5, CSS3/SASS, JavaScript, React, and Node.js to meet clients' requirements.

- Utilized MySQL and PostgreSQL for efficient database development, ensuring seamless integration with the software.
- Delivered high-quality software solutions aligned with clients' specifications and exceeded their expectations.

Software Engineer

Nov 2019 - Aug 2020

Stutern Limited • Lagos, Nigeria

Full-stack software engineering.

Information Technology Instructor

Jan 2018 - Oct 2019

KingChuks College • Lagos, Nigeria

- Taught ICT to high school students.
- · Organized technology learning programs for teachers and other non-academic staff

PROJECTS

Some of the projects I have built and contributed to include:

- Herel Play: A leisure services company application (https://herelplay.com).
- Abbey Mortgage Bank: Built for Abbey Mortgage Bank. The premier, largest mortgage bank in Nigeria for customers to use and access online banking services (https://corporate.abbeymortgagebank.com)
- VBiz: A corporate banking application specifically built for companies and corporate entities (https://business.vbank.ng)
- **Expense Portal:** An expense management application built for corporate entities to track their expenses, budget, approvals, and disbursement (https://expenseapp.vfdgroup.com)

CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals March 2021
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals March 2020
- Understanding of Cisco Network Devices February 2020
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (Routing and Switching) August 2019
- Critical Thinking Skills for Decision Making, Tom Associates June 2023
- Personal Productivity and Development Program, McTimothy Associates September 2022